foreign
[Music]
ly I found myself appreciating the sound
of nature spending more time without
distractions simply being and listening
that is one of the most powerful tools I
have in combating those internal
stresses that often accumulate
throughout our days particularly when
work and relationships and busyness take
over it's natural to get caught up in
these things
but what is unnatural I believe is never
taking a moment to slow down and allow
yourself to be in the company of your
thoughts even for only a few minutes in
the midst of a hectic day
[Music]
doing this helps me sustain a peaceful
mind and befriend my own thinking
allowing those tensions and worries to
show themselves not as monsters that
will make me want to run away instead
they are simply a part of life and it's
up to me to improve my relationship with
my feelings I can learn to manage
anxiousness in order to slowly create
the daily experience I yearn for not a
perfect experience not without its
tricky moments but overall much improved
foreign
I made a video a while ago on how
anxiety has impacted me on a level that
at one point I could no longer function
normally
since then I've made enormous progress
I first started tackling my relationship
with anxiety by working very hard at it
I went overboard policing my own
thoughts and trying to control what I
thought and how I felt sometimes I would
shut down my emotions altogether and tap
out for hours watching a TV show or
desperately trying to avoid being in
quiet this inevitably made things worse
over time
so I realized I had to transform my
method
[Music]
instead of treating my daily hikes as
workouts I started to treat them as
mindful walking experiences where the
movements I took were more rhythmic not
too fast nor slow but steady and I did
my best to focus on my senses on touch
and sound if you're someone like myself
who experiences anxiety in their entire
body not just their mind and can often
feel like they just want to stay in bed
and hide away from everything these
gentle movements have slowly over the
course of months changed a lot for me
foreign
[Music]
I've been working on this little
terrarium for the better part of an hour
and it's been for the most part in
silence I've been listening to my own
breathing listening a little bit to the
little water fountain I have running in
the corner of my home
my cat playing the sounds of the birds
and the squirrels outside
it is amazing how once you slow down and
start listening how much noise there
actually is to often enjoy or that is
interesting or hopefully calming I think
if you are in an apartment or in some
place that is quite busy Outdoors you
may enjoy playing some ambient nature
sounds in your home or have a water
fountain like I do I have found working
on simple but focused little projects
like this is so important for me
especially doing it as a sort of ritual
of quiet contemplation and listening and
mindful breathing
it does wonders for calming I love
little projects like this as well
because they bring nature from the
outside to the inside and I find that
being in a home with plants with other
life with a sort of family that relies
on you to take care of it and to keep
watch over it is also something that
really helps me as well with that being
said I think I'm gonna spend several
hours working on some work projects and
then hopefully when the day is done I
will spend a little bit of time
journaling if I get the opportunity I
highly recommend giving a terrarium a
try they look so beautiful in the house
you might want to design them several
different ways depending on what type of
plant you are going to use so I'll leave
some links down below if you're
interested to learn more
foreign
[Music]
it benefits me to write down my thoughts
and feelings each day while also taking
time to write myself a kind and
encouraging response to how I feel doing
this consistently has helped me problem
solve and manage much better
so much of our media is designed to
elicit strong emotional reactions and
for me I need to make sure not to be
overloaded and in a way allow boredom
and other experiences into my life they
have an incredible ability to kick-start
our healing journey and creativity
staining relationships work career
Community projects and all sorts of
other things are incredibly beneficial
to me but they do leave their Mark and
sometimes I do find myself anxious at
the end of the day so these are some
things that have helped me perhaps they
will help you as well
[Music]
foreign
I have been working on these paintings
for a couple weeks and they're so small
and that I've been just using the very
smallest paint brushes I have and it
takes a very long time and you need to
be quite patient
my grand plan is that by the time this
video is up
I will have made these into prints for
my little Etsy shop however in
preparation I wanted to accompany some
of these art pieces with poems and I
find that writing poetry is perhaps
one of the most healing writing
practices I have done throughout my life
apart from journaling which I started
recently which I didn't do before but
has been extremely helpful for calming
me and helping me settle down at the end
of the day perhaps it's just because I'm
creatively inclined but poetry has just
always had very special place in my
heart and I don't always think I write
good poetry at all I think that
sometimes it's quite horrendous poetry
but I do like to just continue trying
and working with words because I've
always felt the words I use and the
words I put out into the world
you know reflect on me so I will share
an example of the poem draft I'm working
on
the little mouse sleeps in a field of
thistle down ever Amazed by The Wonder
of a quiet world
these are sacred days he whispers to
Rabbit
a slumber once again takes hold they
Traverse a valley of shared dreams and
lie beneath the twilight realm speaking
Noble things we already know yet often
forget upon waking
and I have one more draft of a different
poem to accompany my stag because I
wanted to do a painting of a stack for a
very long time and so I finally did
complete one a simple one at that but I
did want to do a little poem for that
one as well
I am the guardian of the fairy folk upon
the golden Glen you will find me
prancing along the forest path over
fairy rings and memories that you left
as you wandered by Lantern light
Barefoot and hopeful that someday you
will find the source of the Wonder be
patient o Sweet Child and let your light
guide you
that little poem I'm gonna take with me
on my Twilight walk with Iger this
evening and I'm going to read it out
loud Under the Stars
and I think it's just a really lovely
and calming ritual that always ends the
day with a lot of mindfulness and
meaning and it always reminds me to stop
and take a moment to appreciate how the
day's gone because it is so easy to rush
through the days long story short I find
that embracing that sort of um boredom I
don't I don't feel like that's the
appropriate word but it's the only one I
can think of of when you kind of are
free from distractions and quick
gratification particularly in the form
of technology I find that I absolutely
love technology but if I often use it
too much I find that it is so easy to
fill up my minutes instead of allowing
myself to have some time to just simply
be and simply think if I use these
minutes differently how would I want to
use them and how could that benefit me
calm quiet focus in the way that it
heals my body and my kind of more
physical feelings of anxiety when I'm
having a difficult day is magical now
that I've been painting for quite a
while and my neck is quite stiff I'm
going to go upstairs and get changed and
get prepared for a little Twilight walk
with Iger I'm sending all of you my love
do take care of yourselves I send you
all the encouragement to work towards
any healing you're looking for or simply
finding more balance into your day I
think always the key is to embrace the
process of coming to understand what it
is you need to lead a happier life I was
recently gifted these stackable
watercolor trays and I highly recommend
them they're multiple layers and then
you
have a little cover for them I find that
my watercolors take a little bit longer
to dry out so that's always quite useful
it's already getting dark
[Music]
foreign